Admittedly, my kicks aren't the most fancy or flashy in the world.
I don't kick people in the head standing up.
If I'm going to kick him in the head, I'm going to knock him down to the ground first, and then I'll kick him in the head where I don't have to stretch that far.
A side kick is a good technique.
A side kick, basically the way I do it, is I stand sideways to my partner, I'm going to take a step in, cross, kick up and out.
When I kick, I'm kicking with the outside edge of my foot, here, (demo) and then back.
One, two.
(demo) One, two, three, four.
(demo) My target, of course, will be anywhere on the body.
I prefer to kick in the legs, but for this example, I'm going to kick in the body (demo) just like this.
(demo) I could have an attacker dealing with me over on this side, and I may have to kick him to stop him from grabbing while I deal with this other attacker.
What I might want to do, instead of kicking the body like I said, here, (demo) is come in and kick the leg out.
You can have a lot of good effects kicking someone's knee out just like this.
(demo) If you're to the side of the person, (demo) kick out the inside of the leg.
Or, you can kick out the outside of the leg (demo) just like this.
Now, I'm doing that really easy because you can damage the person's knee.
But you'll see the way the leg folds (demo) just by kicking on the outside. Switch your feet. Or, the inside (demo) just like that.
Again, be very careful of practicing these kicks because you can roll the knee out and twist the ankle and the knee at the same time.
But, I think it's a great way to kick, bring it up, out, (demo) just like this.